# Marco Maida

Computer scientist



www.maida.me



mmaidacs@gmail.com

## About me —

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember.

I started working professionally as a developer in 2013. After three years, I started working as game developer while studying part-time as a bachelor's student.

Once I graduated, I moved to Germany and started a joint master's and Ph.D. program. In 2022 I completed my Master's program and first-authored a research paper.

After an internship at Bloomberg LP in New York City, I decided to suspend my Ph.D. and return to the industry. I moved to London and started working at Wayve Ltd, building autonomous driving technologies.

# Languages ——

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am fluent in English,

und ich spreche etwas **Deutsch**.

## Trivia ———

I love camping and traveling with my bike: I often do the two together • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right • I love simplicity • I am striving not to be the smartest person in the room • I often relax by walking on a tensioned rope • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

#### Skills

I have more than **ten years of professional experience**. I extensively worked with **Python**, **C**#, **C**++, **C**, **Java**, **Rust** and **Coq** code. I have a mixed background of **industry** and **academia**.

I am comfortable working on **complex code bases** in large and small teams, and I quickly get used to new technologies. I can **analyze problems** and then design, implement, evaluate, document, and present my solutions.

I am **outgoing** and I **love working in teams**. Due to my game development background, I am used to collaborating with different professional figures (e.g., artists, designers, musicians) and I have an eye for **user experience**.

#### Experience

Since 2022	Software engineer. Working on autonomous driving technologies (C-	Wayve Ltd ++, Rust, Python).
2022	<b>R&amp;D Intern.</b> I worked on accelerating SAT solving using GPUs	Bloomberg LP (C++, CUDA).
2019-2022	<b>PhD Student.</b> I studied timeliness certifications with formal ver	Max Planck Institute ification (COQ) and

on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux (C, Rust). I mentored three interns and published three papers.

2016-2019 Game developer.

34BigThings

I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Switch, and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, dev tools and UIs.

2015-2016 **Freelance Software Engineer.**I built an interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D (C#). I shipped on mobile devices and browsers (JS). I managed one artist I hired and collaborated with another engineer.

2013-2016 **Software engineer.** R.O. srl I developed software solutions for glass processing factories. I started as a developer (C, C++, C#, SQL) and later transitioned to planning new features and managing a small team ( $\leq$  5 people).

## Education

2019-2022	Master in Computer Science.	Technische Universität Kaiserslautern
2016-2019	Bachelor in Computer Science.	Università degli studi di Torino
2015-2016	Game dev: Software Development	Event Horizon School.

# Projects and Publications

2022	<b>Treecode.</b> I created an alternative to QR Codes. Messages as unique trees. (www.maida.me/treecode)	Personal re encoded as
2021	Poet - Automatic Proof Generation.  I developed a tool that yields a formally verified scenario software timing analysis. I first-authored a ECRTS2022, winning its outstanding paper award. (https://drops.dagstuhl.de/opus/volltexte/2022/16336/pdf/LIPIcs-Education of the control of the contro	publication at
2018	Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit.	34BigThings

I developed a Unity3D framework and Toolkit.

34BigThings
I developed a Unity3D framework that accelerates the creation of production-ready casual games, paired by a Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the games. (www.github.com/340penThings)

2017 Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4. 34BigThings I developed a framework that control LEDs on Razer's Chroma hardware. This system is used in every Chroma-compatible 34BigThings game. (www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab\_channel=34BigThings)